<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20180717</CreaDate><CreaTime>16032800</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>North American Profile of ISO19115 2003</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">D09PRPO_BATH_20160720_volume.csv</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE" export="False">005</imsContentType></itemProps></DataProperties><SyncDate>20180806</SyncDate><SyncTime>16204900</SyncTime><ModDate>20180806</ModDate><ModTime>16204900</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>NAP</ArcGISProfile></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE"> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.4.1.5713</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"/></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">D09PRPO_BATH_20160720_volume.csv</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><idPurp>Bathymetry and morphology are key parameters for defining the hydrological, physical, chemical, and biological characteristics of lakes and non-wadeable streams. Water level, volume, area, and stage curve relationships provide spatial quantitative information. They also impart a governing role on hydrodynamics, chemical reactions and biotic distribution and productivity. Furthermore, temporal comparisons between bathymetries can be used as an indicator of environmental change by providing information on ecosystem functioning, changes in water turnover times and storage, and catchment erosion-sedimentation rates (Dost and Mannaerts, 2008). Obtaining baseline characteristics, hence, becomes imperative in light of future activities aimed at a better understanding of lake and river dynamics as well as health through time.</idPurp><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Bathymetric maps are obtained using hydroacoustic (sonar) instrumentation and interfaced with differential global positioning system (DGPS) mounted on a boat. Hydroacoustics are utilized to detect the depth of a water body, sediment characteristics as well as the presence or absence, approximate abundance, distribution, size, and behavior of underwater biota.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>NEON is sponsored by the National Science Foundation and operated under a cooperative agreement by Battelle.
</idCredit><searchKeys><keyword>NEON</keyword><keyword>L4</keyword><keyword>Data product</keyword><keyword>Bathymetry</keyword><keyword>Aquatic</keyword><keyword>Core</keyword><keyword>PRPO</keyword><keyword>Prairie Pothole</keyword><keyword>Domain 09</keyword><keyword>Northern Plains</keyword><keyword>North Dakota</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><Consts><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;NEON DATA PRODUCTS ARE PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS OR ANYONE DISTRIBUTING THE NEON DATA PRODUCTS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE NEON DATA PRODUCTS.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Access to NEON field sites is governed by site host policies and permitting requirements. The properties on which NEON infrastructure and observational plots are located are owned by site hosts. Our rights of access and use are defined in formal Land Use Agreements with these landowners and site hosts. Researchers must obtain their own site host permits for their research. Our science and domain field staff can assist in a variety of ways:&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Science staff may assist in evaluating the potential impacts of proposed activities on NEON measurements and observations&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Domain Managers may assist with site host coordination and location of field sampling on site.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Other assistance may be requested and offered as appropriate.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;If you are interested in conducting investigations near NEON infrastructure and/or observational plots, please contact us to discuss your ideas.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;RequestNEONResources@BattelleEcology.org&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst><resMaint xmlns=""><usrDefFreq><duration>Approximately every 5 yrs</duration></usrDefFreq></resMaint><dataChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></dataChar><suppInfo>WGS1984 UTM Zone 14 North</suppInfo><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="007"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="012"/></tpCat></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"/></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004" Sync="TRUE"/></mdChar><distInfo><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Text File</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="007" Sync="TRUE"/></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">non-geographic dataset</mdHrLvName><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20180806</mdDateSt></metadata>
